<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>logging on Tanmay Bhat</title>
    <link>https://tanmay-bhat.github.io/tags/logging/</link>
    <description>Recent content in logging on Tanmay Bhat</description>
    <image>
      <title>Tanmay Bhat</title>
      <url>https://tanmay-bhat.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://tanmay-bhat.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tanmay-bhat.github.io/tags/logging/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Add Custom Label or Key to Records in Fluentd</title>
      <link>https://tanmay-bhat.github.io/posts/how-to-add-custom-labels-or-keys-to-records-in-fluentd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanmay-bhat.github.io/posts/how-to-add-custom-labels-or-keys-to-records-in-fluentd/</guid>
      <description>Fluentd is a powerful log collection and processing tool. In this blog post, I will walk you through the process of adding custom label and key to the log records, so that you can better understand your logs and filter them more effectively.
For example, you might want to add a custom label to your records to indicate the environment in which the log was generated, or the cluster name. This would allow you to filter your logs by environment or cluster name in Elasticsearch or another storage destination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Overview of Syslog Parsing with Fluentd</title>
      <link>https://tanmay-bhat.github.io/posts/syslog-parsing-with-fluentd/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanmay-bhat.github.io/posts/syslog-parsing-with-fluentd/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Syslog logging is a widely used method for collecting and storing log data. It is a standard that is supported by many applications and platforms. In this blog post, we will take a look at the basics of syslog parsing with Fluentd.
What Is Syslog? Syslog is a protocol used for collecting log data from various sources. It is usually used to collect log data from network devices such as routers and switches, as well as from OS and applications.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
